<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>vinniegarcia.com</title>
  <subtitle>Vinnie Garcia&#39;s writings.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/" />
  <updated>2025-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Vinnie Garcia</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Tending to the Garden</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/15/tending-to-the-garden/" />
    <updated>2025-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/15/tending-to-the-garden/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to get organized, Vinnie!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad seared these words into my brain when I was a teenager. I didn&#39;t understand them at the time, or maybe I didn&#39;t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to understand. But not being organized has bitten me in the ass more times than I can count. I&#39;ve been trying to get better at it, and in no way can I say I&#39;m great at it, but I am trying new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Digital Gardening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I just dumped my stuff into folders and never looked at them again. I&#39;ve been carrying a lot of junk! Junk I never even looked at after it was created or used! So I&#39;m trying to clear that stuff out. I thought it would be useful one day, but it hasn&#39;t. I didn&#39;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paperwork&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paperwork is a mess, frequently. There are times where I have avoided getting the mail so it doesn&#39;t add to the pile. I&#39;m better now about just processing it. But I have a folder of stuff from the past year that needs a pass through. And most of my bills are paid automatically, but I still need to keep track of them. And it always seems like there are more of those than I can track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way I&#39;ve found to be organized at work is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the list of work to be done when you begin your day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort it by (time/importance/whatever criteria is important to you)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on each item top to bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross the items off as you go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the day ends, review your complete items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move your incomplete items to the top of the list for the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new items to the bottom of the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m at my best when I both know what I need to do and can offload what I don&#39;t need to immediately do to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Does this really help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah it does, when I am consistent and diligent about these things. Am I? No. But I&#39;m trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad was around my age when he told me to get organized. I almost took it as a personal attack at the time. He was just warning me. He had spent years being bitten by disorganized times and was trying to help me avoid the same fate. I still learned this the hard way, but I&#39;m better off for it. Thanks Dad, I appreciate you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Habituation</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/14/habituation/" />
    <updated>2025-03-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/14/habituation/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch your thoughts, they become your words; watch your words, they become your actions; watch your actions, they become your habits; watch your habits, they become your character; watch your character, it becomes your destiny. - Lao Tzu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a creature of habit. The familiar is easy to stick to and difficult to escape sometimes. That can lead to bad habits too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve built good habits recently, and I&#39;m proud of them. But I&#39;m also aware that I need to keep working on them. I need to keep practicing them. I need to keep reinforcing them. I need to keep making them a part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habits are muscle builting. I&#39;m working on the muscle-building of writing right now. Maybe I won&#39;t write the greatest magnum opus ever each day, but I will do my best to write something. Even if I&#39;m the only reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making Websites Is Fun Again</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/13/making-websites-is-fun-again/" />
    <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/13/making-websites-is-fun-again/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t touch this website for 10 years since the last version. I finally redesigned it this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 4 months, I&#39;ve made four websites myself and helped a friend breathe new life into three of his websites. I hadn&#39;t done that much work outside of my day job in years. It felt great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the absence was just being tired. After decades of working on software, and after a long day, sometimes the last thing you want to do is work on something like a website or app. You just want to spend time with family, or have a good dinner, or walk the dog and relax when you finish work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of it was just feeling like I had nothing to say, or being afraid to put it out there. I&#39;m getting over that general feeling. But specifically, I&#39;m going to put more here than just tech stuff. I&#39;ll put things I make, or places I go, or philosophies on life and the mind and whatever I feel like. This is my website. I&#39;m going to determine what to put on it and not be afraid to express myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet and the web are not what they were when this website started in 2003 (yes, this website is old enough to buy alcohol!). It&#39;s less friendly, more corporate, more walled off. Instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BUaTsSMSbcU&quot;&gt;five giant websites, each with screenshots of the other four&lt;/a&gt;, people ran their own sites. I used to do that, and I missed it, so here I am again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rules for being human handed down from ancient Sanskrit</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/12/rules-for-being-human-handed-down-from-ancient-sanskrit/" />
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/12/rules-for-being-human-handed-down-from-ancient-sanskrit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive a body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will learn lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no mistakes, only lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lesson is repeated until it is learned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning lessons does not end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;There&amp;quot; is no better than &amp;quot;Here.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others are merely mirrors of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What you make of your life is up to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The answers lie inside you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your answers lie inside you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will forget all of this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can remember it whenever you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rules date back to circa 1500BC. They play in my head a lot, especially lately. Different ones at different times in my life, but they&#39;re usually in the background or foreground somewhere. They&#39;re great reminders of the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will forget them again. And I will remember them again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Just Start</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/09/just-start/" />
    <updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/09/just-start/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I often think of an idea. Then I write it down. Then I make plans to work on it. Then I don&#39;t work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made plans to work on this site for 10 years. I haven&#39;t touched it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&#39;s start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is this about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s about me. This used to be about my work, but that&#39;s limiting. I hope to add more than that. I do more than just my work. I want to do a good job there, but it&#39;s not the biggest or most rewrarding part of my life; that would be my family and loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll keep these posts around or delete them from time to time. It doesn&#39;t really matter. I am here again and I will make this relevant for right now and for later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>