<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>vinniegarcia.com</title>
  <subtitle>Vinnie Garcia&#39;s writings.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/" />
  <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Vinnie Garcia</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Making Websites Is Fun Again</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/12/making-websites-is-fun-again/" />
    <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/12/making-websites-is-fun-again/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t touch this website for 10 years since the last version. I finally redesigned it this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 4 months, I&#39;ve made four websites myself and helped a friend breathe new life into three of his websites. I hadn&#39;t done that much work outside of my day job in years. It felt great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the absence was just being tired. After decades of working on software, and after a long day, sometimes the last thing you want to do is work on something like a website or app. You just want to spend time with family, or have a good dinner, or walk the dog and relax when you finish work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of it was just feeling like I had nothing to say, or being afraid to put it out there. I&#39;m getting over that general feeling. But specifically, I&#39;m going to put more here than just tech stuff. I&#39;ll put things I make, or places I go, or philosophies on life and the mind and whatever I feel like. This is my website. I&#39;m going to determine what to put on it and not be afraid to express myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet and the web are not what they were when this website started in 2003 (yes, this website is old enough to buy alcohol!). It&#39;s less friendly, more corporate, more walled off. Instead of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BUaTsSMSbcU&quot;&gt;five giant websites, each with screenshots of the other four&lt;/a&gt;, people ran their own sites. I used to do that, and I missed it, so here I am again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rules for being human handed down from ancient Sanskrit</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/11/rules-for-being-human-handed-down-from-ancient-sanskrit/" />
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/11/rules-for-being-human-handed-down-from-ancient-sanskrit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will receive a body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will learn lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no mistakes, only lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lesson is repeated until it is learned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning lessons does not end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;There&amp;quot; is no better than &amp;quot;Here.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others are merely mirrors of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What you make of your life is up to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The answers lie inside you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your answers lie inside you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will forget all of this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can remember it whenever you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rules date back to circa 1500BC. They play in my head a lot, especially lately. Different ones at different times in my life, but they&#39;re usually in the background or foreground somewhere. They&#39;re great reminders of the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will forget them again. And I will remember them again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Just Start</title>
    <link href="https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/08/just-start/" />
    <updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://vinniegarcia.com/2025/03/08/just-start/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I often think of an idea. Then I write it down. Then I make plans to work on it. Then I don&#39;t work on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made plans to work on this site for 10 years. I haven&#39;t touched it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&#39;s start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is this about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s about me. This used to be about my work, but that&#39;s limiting. I hope to add more than that. I do more than just my work. I want to do a good job there, but it&#39;s not the biggest or most rewrarding part of my life; that would be my family and loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll keep these posts around or delete them from time to time. It doesn&#39;t really matter. I am here again and I will make this relevant for right now and for later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>